A Guide to the Jean Von Schilling genealogical research collection
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Jean Von Schilling genealogical research collection,
The Library of Virginia
45087
.45 cubic feet (1 box)
Jean Von Schilling
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Jean Von Schilling, Richmond.
Biographical Information
Genealogical materials collected by Jean Von Schilling of Richmond, Virginia, containing information on the Brent, Newman, Phillips, Wade, Wills, Winder, and Wynne families of Fauquier, James City, and York Counties, Virginia. Also contains information on Grafton Baptist Church in York County, Virginia, and Lebanon Christian Church in Newport News, Virginia; as well as information on the Disciples of Christ and religion in Virginia.
Contents List
- The Brents: Four Brother in Gray in News and Notes from the Fauquier Historical Society, 1994; Newman family; The Newman Story, 1618-1958, 1958; Phillips family letter, 11 June, 1998 (Folder 1)
- Wade family: Memories of Other Days by Sarah Wade Gray; Elizabeth Wade diary, transcribed 1985; The Wade Family of York County, Survivors of the Peninsula Campaign by Frederick Wills Boelt (Folder 2)
- Wills family: Ancestors of Thomas Wills by Mary Catharine Murphy, 1967; Working Notes on Wills Family of Mulberry Island by Fred Eggleston, 1997 (Folder 3)
- Winder family: John Winder and Four Generations of Descendants by Elizabeth Hogg Ironmonger, 1975; Edward Thomas Winder--My Great-Grandfather by Thelma Ironmonger Hansford, 1995 (Folder 4)
- Wynne family: genealogical charts of related families; Wynne Family (Folder 5)
- Wynne family: Charlton family; Thomas George Wynne Green Mount Journal, 1861; article on William H. Wynne with Wynne family genealogy; and article on the 32nd Virginia Infantry (Folder 6)
- Wynne family: History of Grafton Baptist Church York County, Virginia Constituted in 1777 by L. Peyton Little, published 1932, copies 1938; Dr. Edward Camm Wynne: Descendants and Ancestors by Bower R. Patrick, III, 1990 (Folder 7)
- Grafton Church Cemetery Book (York County, Va.) (Folder 8)
- A History of Lebanon Christian Church by J. Virgil Lilly (Folder 9)
- Ante-Bellum Virginia Disciples: An Account of the Emergence and Early Development of the Disciples of Christ in Virginia by H. Jackson Darst, 1959 (Folder 10)
- The Reformation of the 19th Century on the Virginia Peninsula by James D. Massey, 1984 (Folder 11)